Lisa and I first met in PUBG
Back then, Lisa sent me a DM right after our first match together
She sent me a friend request right away
"If you could, please be friends with me!"
She said something like that
L: Yeah, like, after playing with people, I...
L: I'd ask them, like, "Please tell me your Twitter account!"
Yeah, you were, like, "Please tell me your Twitter account!"
L: I asked you straight away, right?
Yeah, you did
I thought it was cute
L: At first, it was really --
Q: There aren't many girls who play games, after all, right?
L: Exactly
L: It was the first time I had played with a girl with such great vibes
Really? That makes me happy <3
That was how I met Lisa
This was way back, before we even joined VSPO
The Lisa back then was so pretty
L: What about now?
Now, you're, like... ww
My impression of you has changed ww
L: Well, I'm probably like *that* when meeting people for the first time
L: I don't get too... excited, so..
Q: You didn't? Oh, but you definitely do so now, right?
L: Well, now I do
Oh, but I remember thinking you were good
I was, like, "Wow, so there are girls who are this good, huh.."
L: What happened to PUBG? I heard there was a PUBG2, but..
Oh, really?
If it comes out, I'd like to give it a try
L: Okay, then let's play it
Mhm
Lisa and I were friends before joining.
Y'all must be quite surprised, huh?
And, I want you all to listen to this --
Way before I was set to join VSPO,
When Lisa and I were still just friends,..
About once every two weeks,
Lisa would send me a strange DM
L: www
This was before I was in VSPO, okay?
L: *exhale*
About once every two weeks, late at night,
she'd say something like, "Beni-chan.. "
"Would you eat an onigiri I made?"
Isn't that creepy as fuck?!
It's not like we were THAT close, you know?
ww
Back when we were still acquaintances at best.. ww
L: I mean.. ww
Q: Huh? That's creepy as hell, though?
L: Why would you say something like that?
Q: What happened? What made you (send DMs like that)?
They were totally out of the blue!
L: Back then, I seriously had no friends, and..
www
Q: www
L: Don't you ever suddenly feel like randomly hanging out with someone when it's late at night or something?
Q: You were lonely, huh?
www
L: It'd be fine if I had friends who I could talk to when I felt like that, but I didn't, so..
ww
L: So, um.. I DMed somebody who didn't seem like they would get mad if I randomly contacted them
It was seriously freaky, you know?
L: So I sent horrible DMs to Beni
I even went to others for advice about this, you know?
If it were just once, I'd let it go,
but after the second, and then the third..
I thought, "This girl's seriously off her rockers"
L: www
Seriously ww
I told a mutual friend, "There's this girl called Lisa who DMed me,"
"asking if I would eat onigiri she made. I'm scared!"
TLN: Drugs, maybe. I'll have a couple Lisa onigiri
Q: You'd think it was a codeword or something
Exactly!
When I asked our mutual friend, she was, like,
"Well, she's a weird one, after all"
L: You're making me sound like I've actually got problems! Stop it ww
Q: ww
L: So I was that much of a bother to you, huh..
No, not at all -- I found it funny
L: Really? ww
Yeah ww
To be honest, I was freaked out,
but I thought, "She's a strange one, isn't she?"
L: www
L: But you didn't cut me off because of that, so..
Well, of course!
L: So you're a good person.
Since I like you as a person.
Even you send me a scary DM..
You seemed normal when we talked, so I was like, "What's going on?"
I was always wondering what was up with you
L: mou~ (embarrassed)