Ichinose Uruha
Vspo
Inuyama Tamaki
NoriPro
If I recall, weren't the two of us in the
same discord server at one point?
Do you remember that?
Yes, I remember
I think it was Meika-kun's call-in stream or something
I was like, "Oh! Ichinose-san's here!",
so I sent you a friend request
And you quickly accepted
But, after that, didn't you send a hand waving emoji? 👋
Well, I suddenly got a friend request from you,
so I thought I might have done something
I was pretty surprised, so I decided to
just send you a hand wave for starters
Ah, so you were just testing out the waters with that?
I sent it like, "Ah, did you need something?"
Well, this was just my arbitrary impression of you,
but I didn't think you were the type to
send a hand wave, but you did! Seeing that,
I thought, "Oh! Ichinose Uruha's the
hand waving type," so I waved my hand back
Right, like, "Hello" "Good afternoon"
Right, and after saying stuff like "Nice to meet you" and
"Thank you for accepting my friend request,"
TLN: after Tamaki shows her good intentions, Ichinose replies that she had mistakenly assumed why Tamaki wanted to talk to her.
I got something like, "Ah, I was wrong"
Yeah, I was pretty confused and afraid, like,
"I got something from Inuyama Tamaki?"
Of course, like, suddenly --
Even though we hadn't had any prior interaction,
nor were we entering together in some sort of tournament,
you would wonder why I was contacting you, right?
Well, in the first place, I don't really participate
in the FPS scene, so there wasn't much chance
for us to be in the same Discord server.
So when we were in Meika's server, I saw that Ichinose
was there, and thought, "Lucky!", and sent you a
friend request, but it seems like
you were a bit surprised by that
I was actually happy about it. I mean, it's not often
that you get friend requests, right?
Well, I guess not
But someone like me, who just randomly sends
friend requests, is quite rare, especially in
this industry, where most people are fairly reticent.
I saw it and was happy about it
Thank you very much
That said, after I invited you for this stream,
which you accepted, it's been several months, but have
you ever been on any other talking-focused streams?
Personally, I don't really think of myself as very suitable
for such streams, but Tamaki's conversation streams are
you know, quite well-known, right?
Ah, well, the guests are well-known, yup.
I had seen a couple of them, and thought they were
interesting, so I was really happy
when you invited me on
As damage control, I preemptively said,
"I have zero confidence, but if you're okay
with me, I'd be glad to participate."
Right, you were like, "I'm totally ill-suited for this,
and I don't know if I'll be able to talk, is that
okay?", and I said that that was totally fine
Well, some say I have Predator-level communication skills
For real, my intent today was to completely rely on you
Today, when we were meeting up, I asked Ichinose,
"Is it alright if I'm really talkative today?," and she was like,
"Oh, I came today hoping you'd do exactly that, so I'd
be in a bit of a pinch if we can't make that happen"
That's what I was thinking coming into this.
Thank you, then let's get talking a bunch
I plan to talk about a lot of different topics with Nose today
Okay, then, how about we start with the first question?
Alright, let's see what it is
"Please tell us how you came to know of each other
and what your respective first impressions were."
Well, this is a fairly orthodox opener, but let's see..
Nose-san, do you remember when you
first learned of Inuyama Tamaki?
Inuyama Tamaki.. it was probably a clip, but I don't
remember which one specifically, since it was a
while ago, but I think you were with Kagura Mea...
The clip was absolutely not wholesome at all,
if I had to say, it was downright nasty.
I watched that and thought it was interesting.
That's how I learned of you.
That's a terrible way to do so
My impression of you was... fairly... strong...
So you probably thought of me as someone
who got along with and resembled Kagura Mea
That's right
That kind of first impression... I don't like it..
I imagined you to be a foul-mouthed sort of person
Ah, I see
I came with that impression
But, now, you think of me as a strong communicator, right?
Ah, now.. I think you're good at talking, and, I
: also, your thumbnails are really good, cute,
and easy on the eyes. Something like that.
I'd totally be willing to make thumbnails for you
Actually, recently.. Recently?
I bought *that* recently, you know, Photoshop
Recently?!
Nose-san, how long have you been a VTuber for, again?
Three years..
Oh, man, it's been a while
I bought it to commemorate 3 years
To commemorate three years, huh? I see, so three years
is the bare minimum before using Photoshop.
So, I bought it and started looking at how
other people were making their thumbnails, and, while
I was doing that, I saw Tamaki-san's thumbnails
Really? That makes me glad
I thought they were good
Nose-san, I can teach you how to use Photoshop
Please do so
I want to run a thumbnail making course
I really want you to do so
Should I? Let's do it over at Nose-san's channel, then
Please, I'll watch the archive over and over
You're really keen about this, aren't you?
I'll use it as reference
Well, moving on from thumbnails, how I first found
out, how I first *properly* found out, about Nose-san
actually had something to do with Kagura Mea
I was searching about myself on the Internet,
and there were results about Kagura Mea and how
her room was, well, can't be said to be clean,
as it's freaking disgusting, but, Nose-san's room,
without sugar-coating it, is pretty bad, too, right?
That's true ww
So, with this uncommon common ground, you and
Kagura Mea were seen as "comrades in filth," and
there were search results expressing a desire to see the
two of you duke it out over the filthiness of your rooms
That's illogical, since Kagura Mea and I
have had zero interactions thus far
So, I don't really want to be compared with her
While Mea-chan's room isn't as clean as if it were cleaned by professionals,
but it isn't so bad that things would
start growing if she didn't bathe
Nose-san's different, right?
I'm sorry, but I don't want to be
compared with her. That's too much, even for me
I thought, "Ichinose Uruha's is so cute, there's no way
she can be *that* filthy, right?", so I went and looked it up
Something like, "Ichinose Uruha Room"
Then, a bunch of results showed up:
"Dirty room," "Filthy room," "Unbelievable...," etc.
I was like, "No way! Even though she's
that cute, her room is actually filthy?"
It's true that my room is disgusting.
I can't say anything to that.
"Even though she's cute...," I thought.
And, with that, my image of Ichinose Uruha pretty much disintegrated.
Oh, is that so? So, when you saw me at first, it was, like..
A cool, cute..  Right, a cute and cool girl who
was good at games. Something like that.
Ah, is that right?
I initially thought that your room being dirty was
just a meme, but after seeing VSpo members' reactions,
I knew it wasn't a joke
It isn't a joke
When I heard that you walking around your room
produces audible sounds of objects rustling about,
I was like "Ahhh..."
Things were pretty bad, back then
Well, it seems like it hasn't been that bad recently, but..
That said, my first impression of you came from talk of
how filthy your room was, but after you accepted my
invitation for this collab, we've come to
talk a lot more, and, well, what I started thinking was...
Maybe I should choose my words carefully here, but,
TLN: menhera, from  'mental healthers' on 2-chan. Now, commonly used to describe people, usually women, who are clingy/pushy/obsessive.
Nose-san is a bit obsessive (menhera) , aren't you?
???
Like, the way you communicate, how should I say this...
How often you contact the other person,
TLN: 連絡マメ, literally, "contact bean." To be a 'bean' is to be diligent, positive, earnest.
I thought it's a bit, *that*, you know?
Like, you really pay attention to (replying to) messages
Oh, really?
I thought  it was adorable, and thought that you
resembled some of the other obsessive women I've known
TLN: マメ. See previous TLN.
No way, you really think I'm earnest?
Yes, you are. In the VTuber industry,
Nose-san definitely is.
Ah, but, you know, people in this industry..
are slow to reply, aren't they?
True, they don't reply after 3 days, while Nose-san
replies quickly, and when you explain something,
you also include emojis
Well, when I'm talking to people whom
I've just met, I try my hardest to use emojis
That's impressive!
Like, I think that they might be a bit reserved towards me,
so I try to add emojis
Getting your feelings across is pretty difficult via texting, isn't it?
TLN: Can't quite hear whether she says 'one' or 'two'
I try to reply to every one or two messages
But, you know, in my experience, people like that tend to
want others to reply as quickly as they do, and get a bit
crazy if that doesn't happen, but, what about you?
TLN: LINE is a popular messaging app in Japan. Similar to sending a message on WhatsApp, WeChat, etc. after being ghosted on Discord/email/etc.
I'm actually fine if they don't reply. If they don't, I'll just hit them up on LINE
ah.. so you're *that* type...
I think she also came here, but, Hinano et al.
sometimes never reply to messages.
When that happens, I message them on LINE.
If she doesn't reply on Discord, I'll send something like, "Hey??? Reply?" on LINE.
With the other members, too, I repeatedly @mention them,
like, "reply? reply?? reply???"
Like, Nazu-chan, right?
ww Yeah, Nazu-chan, too. I @mention them like, "sup?"
I see, so that's what you're like.
Listen up, everyone, there's two patterns to menhera:
If you don't reply to their messages, they either
go crazy and start cutting their wrists, or
they repeatedly try to contact you.
Right, I don't cut my wrists, but I'll contact you incessantly
Ah, if you were the type that cut their wrists,
you'd probably continue until your hands fell off, huh?
That's right
I'll also call their phone
Ahh! You'd also phone them?!
I do! If it's a message that I want them to reply
to immediately, I send around two messages, and
if they don't reply to those, I call their phone
Alright, then.. I'll give my phone number.
I'm pretty quick at replying, so I think
I should be fine, though...
Ah, please. Then, if there's any urgent replies
I need from you, I'll give you a phone call
That's right, if someone doesn't reply to you,
you might think that they've come to dislike you,
which isn't very good, right?
Oh, but if it's unimportant,
I don't really care if they reply or not
Oh, that's kind of nice
I'd be like, "Oh, whatever."
So, if you had plans to go out and they don't reply,
you'd just be like, "Huh? What's up with that?"
Plans to go out... if they don't reply, that's fine.
Oh, really?
Plans to go out, well, I'm pretty much a homebody, so
if plans to go out fall through, I'd just think,
"Cool, I don't have to go out. Let's get some shut-eye."
Conversely, I'd be like, "Lucky!", and just drop the topic  without saying anything back,
not even a, "Oh, so what should we do instead?"
And, with that, I'd be like, "Okay, how about we just sleep today?"
Wow, this is probably pretty common among streamers
If I had to say, if it's something I'm interested in or curious about, I'll insist on a reply
Ah.. like, "Why aren't you replying?"
Yeah, so if I'm like, "What happened to X?" and they don't reply, I'd just send the same message again
So you do it until they reply?
Yeah, I do it until they reply
Well, looks like we've heard a bit about Nose-san's
personality, but let's ask her about her room. Here we go.
"I want to hear about how you hired professional cleaners to clean your room.
I'd also like to hear about how your room is recently."
First off, how's your room look right now, Nose-san? Is it clean?
Right now... ww.. Let's see..
There's some udon that I ate three or four days ago...
(far away from the mic) Pasta from 3 days ago..
Ahh, no way!
and sara udon that I ate yesterday.. ?
TLN: sara udon (皿うどん), lit. 'plate noodles.' Typical fried noodles.
That's way too much..
That's what I've got lying around
That's what I've got behind me, right now
They're in plastic bags, right.. ?
No, they're not
Huh?! N-n-no way!
You mean, you don't have them tied up in the
plastic bags that come in (via UberEats)?
No, I don't.
Wait up...
I've just left them as is
Then, what if you accidentally knock something over, e.g. with your feet?
Oh, I've sort of established where I can put them so that doesn't happen
I've got a sort of 'perimeter' set up
Amazing! So you have something like a 'garbage zone'?
Yeah, I have a zone for the garbage that just barely doesn't intrude on my personal space
In the first place, it's pretty bad for garbage to be part of your personal space
That's bizarre...
You've had times where there was so much
garbage piled up that you couldn't move your chair, right?
That's right. Now, I've got a cleaner who comes by,
so I don't have that problem anymore.
You say that, but, don't they come around once a week?
Yeah, once every two weeks.
Every *two* weeks?
Then, isn't it pretty bad the day before they come?
It is. So when they come, I tell them,
"It's bad today," or, "It's clean today."
No way ww
(To tell them,) I turn around in the middle of a zatsudan stream and face my room
You've gotten close with them ww
Yeah, we get along quite well, like, "Yeah, today's pretty bad."
If they came to the room in which such a cute girl is living and saw that it was so filthy,
that would definitely leave an impression, for sure
I guess so ww
You're getting along with them..
What kind of mentality do you have to talk to them like that?
Well, initially, I was quite embarrassed, like,
"I'm so sorry that it's this dirty"
But, they replied, "Ah, it's because there are people
like yourself that we have our jobs, so please don't
pay it any mind," so I stopped minding it so much,
and now, I'm like, "Ah, it's about this dirty today."
So you've gotten quite flippant about it
Yeah, I have, quite arrogantly
TLN: Someone who only has good/reassuring things to say to/about you.
Well, there's nothing wrong about it, but the cleaner-san is like your mirror
That's true, they were like, "It's alright, don't worry about it," so I stopped worrying about it.
I've heard that you've had enough plastic bottles
piled up that you can hear them when you move around,
but how many do you have right now?
Right now...
Right now, I've got eight. Just before --
Wait a second, you're saying eight like it's a small number,
but, normally, you wouldn't have eight, right?!
No, it's not much. In the past, not sure when, I said
that I'd clean them up on-stream, and when I did...
If I recall, there were around forty or so...
How many people are living with you?
You've got forty people there or something?
No, it's just me in this room ww
But, if you think about it, in two weeks,
would you reach 40? Would it?
Would it.. It hasn't been a week since the cleaner last came...
So it gets like that if they don't come...
One or two gets left around, though
Well, yeah, if you're drinking from a 500ml or 1L bottle
That's right. After all, you've got to drink to survive
Wait up, if you're going to live, clean up your trash ww
Really, how are you so arrogant about this?
I mean, you'll die if you don't drink, but
you won't die even if you don't clean up the trash
It's not a matter of life or death. It doesn't reach that level.
You're crazy, for real.
Honestly, you're at the level where you could be
TLN: Hoarders: an American TV show about people who collect a bunch of stuff, usually trash, in their houses.
featured on Hoarders, if you really wanted to, right?
Actually, right now, I'm living with my parents, but..
What the..
you're like this while living with your parents?
On the other hand, it's because I'm living
with my parents that I'm living like this
If I were living alone, you'd probably see me on TV
I'm not bragging about it, though ww
It's definitely not something to boast about, but,
I'd probably go on TV
Why are you so confident when it comes to your room?
If I talk about it on stream like this, well, there aren't
many people like me, right? My rarity is quite high
Well, that's true.. you even have
"Dirty room" added to your Twitter bio.
That's right. I didn't have it at the start, but I added it later, thinking that it works in my favour.
When I first saw Nose-san, like when you first debuted,
before VSpo even had its name,
I'm positive that your bio had no mention
of your room being filthy!
I didn't have it written there, back then
I'm positive it wasn't there, back then...
Just when was it added?
I was like, "This has become part of her identity."
Yeah, I kind of feel good about it
Yeah, it's sort of like, "Speaking of dirty rooms..."
Yeah, people were asking and reaching out to me about it,
so I was like, "Wait, isn't this really nice?"
True, the title of this stream is, "Filthy Room Invasion"
Right, it's used in the title
When I first send the thumbnail for Nose-san to check,
I was thinking, "I might have gone too far with this..."
"This might have been too rude, I'm not sure...,"
But you said, "It's completely fine!",
so I was like, "It's alright?!"
I thought,"Wow, she's being so polite," so when you asked me to check,
I took a look and thought, "This looks completely fine"
No way, I thought that saying, "Filthy Room Invasion"
about a girl would surely be overdoing it
I looked at it and didn't see anything wrong
I was like, "Easy on the eyes, just as always"
That's what drew my attention
So you were like, "Ah, the text is easy to read."
Like, "The words look really good," and,
"The colours work well together"
How much do people make fun of you, usually, Nose-san?
To not feel anything from that is pretty wild
I honestly didn't feel anything
That's crazy, for real. Couldn't you actually go toe-to-toe
with Kagura Mea, Nose-san?
The two of you could fight..
I'm actually curious how dirty Kagura Mea is
I want to show each other our rooms
Should we do that off-stream?
Should you two fight over that?
ww Show each other our room's and see whose is dirtier
Alright, moving on... this one is also a bit unnerving
"Nose-san has spilled soup from left-out cup noodles.
Has Tamaki ever spilled something that disastrous?"
No, I haven't...
"Soup from left-out cup noodles."
In the first place, are cup noodles, with the soup
still inside, something you just leave around?!
Yup
Have some restraint, for real!
This is like beginner level stuff
Ah, so it's pretty much a given in this industry
Yeah, this is one of the first steps you take in this industry
So, this industry had something like knocking over stuff as a first step?
Well, it's like a common mistake you make in life, right?
There's no such thing
No, really, I've never had this happen even once
Ah, so, like, how long you can keep it without knocking it over?
Like, "Hmm.. let's put this somewhere more flat."
Are you doing some sort of contest in your room?
Are you fighting with somebody?
Wait, this... "Left out" -- How long was this left out for?
This is probably about when I spilled cup noodle soup
that I had left out for 2 weeks, I think...
Wait, what happens if you do that? Mold?
What was the soup like, after that?
It was a forest.
Wait, wait, I'm scared. I'm honestly scared!
There were many life -- lifeforms, if you can call them that.
Stars and stuff.
Well, we live on Earth, but there were more stars inside the cup noodles.
So, a new universe was forming inside?
Ah, yes, a new universe was being formed.
Isn't that mold?
Well, I guess that's how it was.
I guess that's what people in this world call it.
Doesn't it smell?
Actually, about that.. Really,
I think that normal people wouldn't get this, but..
What are you laughing about?
Cup ramen.. ww
Well, I just thought that I'll be telling this story
tens of thousands of times throughout my life
Ah, so this isn't the first time?
Yeah. Well, cup noodles have oil in them, right?
They do
So if you cool it and leave it out, the oil will float up, right?
It does
And that oil membrane covers up the smell
Really?!
Yeah, but, even so, it's still probably smellier than your typical room
However, it's probably not as strong an odour as people might be thinking
Really? So that membrane somehow takes care of it, huh?
The membrane probably covers it, and,
well, the smell is probably more manageable once it's formed
It's like you've got a second lid there ww
Are you doing experiments in your room or something?
No, actually, I recently identified the limit of what I can handle
(Recently, as) in the past few years
That's wild
If I were to visit your room, I'd probably vomit since I'm quite sensitive to smells
Are you also a tidy person?
I mean, I'm a middle-aged man living with my
parents, who clean my room for me, so,
if I had to say, I'm probably a tidy person..
Oh, really?
Since you have someone to clean your room for you, I guess we're pretty much the same.
But, you see.. there's no way there's ever going to be
FORTY plastic bottles lying around!
Even if it's not to that extent, you could say we both
have people to clean up after us, or perhaps
that we're being monitored
It's true that we're both middle-aged men living with our parents, but
there's something that's not quite the same, right? Right?
If you (?), we're pretty much on the same level as human beings
True.. we're both grown-ups, so we're pretty much the same...
True! ww
We're comrades.. I can't be so arrogant with Nose-san
That's how it is
I, too, leave my instant noodles out, but they don't turn
into *that* because my parents clean up for me
Right
We're the same
Why is this person so arrogant?!
No, but, everyone tells me I'm arrogant, but, I wonder if everyone cleans up after themselves, you know?
That's true. Then, it's like, "Okay, how about you do it, then?"
That's right
Bizarre..
Like, if people who look at me would do some self-reflection, or something
True, I guess it opens an opportunity for self-reflection, but,
how about we move on.
I'd be glad to hear more about your dirty room, but..
Here we go..
"I heard that Nose-san was exiled to the mountains after an eight-man interview. Did this really happen?"
Looks like we've got another iconic, "Speaking of Nose-san...," episode.
True
In the first place...
I don't really know how to read this, "eight-man interview," "eight-person interview"?
It's a word I've never used before.
Isn't that right?
Why were there eight people there?
Who were they? Who was there?
No, well, back then..
Oh, the members were, let's see..
TLN: It's been a while since I was in K-12, so I don't remember the proper terms for these roles. Also, I went to public schools, so we didn't have all these fancy bigwigs.
My homeroom teacher,
the head of my grade,
the vice principal,
the chairman, the assistant director,
and my parents
Oh, and, what was that called again?
Just now, when I was looking at back on another episode, I forgot the name,
but it was something like the 'disciplinary committee.' It wasn't actually them, though.
Something like a teacher from the disciplinary committee.
Ah, you did mention a teacher from the disciplinary committee.
Ah, right, it was those people.
And thus, eight people.
Weren't there too many people? That's a full house, isn't it?
Well, it was to talk about whether I'd be expelled or not, so we had everyone present.
How did things even get that far?
TLN: Someting like a counselor
Ah, it was the "Life guidance" (teacher).
Ah, the life guidance teacher?
It was the life guidance teacher
Why did such an all-star team get together?
That's... It really wasn't anything major..
If I had to say, it wasn't anything like in manga,
like breaking windows with a bat, or slandering a teacher
It's just that my grades -- to put it nicely, I *did* study,
Even if I didn't, I'd remember everything from class,
so I didn't see the point in attending class
I thought there wasn't much point in going.
Our campus was really nice-looking, with benches and all.
We had something like a clearing (?)
It was a fancy girls' school, right?
Yeah, and I'd play hooky to laze around there and read manga
We had something like a penalty/strike system
Once you racked up enough strikes, you had to write some sort of reflection
Oh, it was a fancy girls' school, so they had that sort of system?
Yeah, we had that sort of system, and I had a bunch of strikes, so..
Oh, so you had enough strikes, huh?
Yeah, and I properly wrote a reflection
So you did, huh?
Like, "I'm sorry."
So you accumulated a bunch of strikes, wrote your reflection, and then accumulated strikes again?
Right, right
That's wild. So you were so out of hand that they held the 8-man meeting?
Yes, that's right
And the topic turned into whether I'd quit
So, were you exiled into mountains after you left?
Umm.. No, I was made to quit while in the mountains
So, when you returned, you found out that you had been expelled?
I returned, and when I thought that I'd go to school,
they told me, "You don't have a place in this school anymore"
"You don't need to wear that uniform anymore."
Huh, really?!
Yeah, so I wasn't able to say that I was going to quit, like, to my classmates.
That alone felt lonely.
They didn't let you even say your farewells?
No, they didn't, since I was expelled.
That's crazy..
That's right
So you were sent into the mountains to reform,
but it wasn't so that you could return to school?
What was it for, even?
So they just wanted you to reform, and sent you into the mountains?
Yeah, and, well, my parents were pretty strict, so
they were like, "You're taking the world too lightly."
Like, "You're taking the eyes of society, way too lightly."
TLN: Lit., could also be "wasn't planned," but she's referring to herself, so I'm pretty sure her parents had arranged it beforehand.
It wasn't something that I knew about beforehand.
One morning, when I woke up,
My parents were in my room
They dragged me --
At the time, they really dragged me out,
I was pretty deep in puberty, so..
I was like, "What the hell?", but they dragged me out to the front door in my pajamas
That's crazy www
They made me get into the car, and..
This sounds like the start of a death game!
And then I got on a train. Something like that.
So, when you arrived, you were in the mountains?
Yup
What did they make you do in the mountain rehab facility?
ww It was just, like, ordinary fieldwork
Actual mountain work, huh?
It was like a proper facility..
They'd take roll call, and we had to make our own meals..
Oh, you made your own meals?
As for a day's tasks, they'd say something like,
"Ok, Ichinose-san, today, you will go to the hill and check on the mushrooms there."
Ah, so they had a hill where they were growing mushrooms, right?
Yeah, they'd be like, "Please go to the hill and check on the mushrooms," and I'd be like, "Ok."
Then, it'd be like, "After that, please harvest the carrots."
So that kind of work must have cleansed your mind, right?
That's right
You've also mentioned how it was actually fun, right?
It was fun! Well, I'm not sure if it's okay for me to say that, but
there were a lot of kids who were like *that* there
Many different kids were there, so...
I see, I see
So it was fun
Huh.. On that note, it seems that Nose-san picked up a skill while in the mountains, let's see..
"Speaking of Nose-san, after having been exiled into the mountains,
she became an expert at stinkbug extermination. I'd like to hear about that."
Does this mean that there were a lot of stinkbugs on the mountain?
There were tons of them. I think it was the season
Like, literally, we were with stinkbugs from morning to night
Like, we'd be woken up in the middle of the night by the sound of them flying
Also, when you wake up, you get up and turn the futon over, right?
When you did that, you'd find stinkbugs
No way (x3)
Right, and, can I say something really scary?
Got it, okay. Please listen carefully, everyone
Well, we hung our clothes to dry, right?
Well, I initially didn't know any better,
so when I tried to put my pants on,
I just tried to wear them directly, right?
When I tried to do that, five or six stinkbugs fell out
*dying*
I had the same reaction at the start, like, "I can't do this!"
Well, of course you'd be taken aback by that.
You'd be in full survival mode.
Yeah, at the time, I was really in survival mode, but I gradually got used to it.
Ah, I guess it just became part of your daily life
Right, so I'd just give my clothes a pat
To brush them off ww
Yeah, like "Let's get them off, let's go, let's go."
I didn't repeat my mistake, ultimately
Stinkbugs don't release their odour unless you agitate them, right?
Oh, there's no smell at all, at least, not immediately.
How did you get rid of them? Packing tape?
We were given plastic bottles with soap and water..
They gave those to you?
Yeah, they came in a set with a pair of disposable chopsticks
What is that set? www
So you'd pick them up with chopsticks and put them inside the plastic bottle
Oh, so that set was all they gave you to deal with the stinkbugs?
Yeah, a set came with each room
They were like, "Use this and take care of the bugs."
ww that's crazy
So that's what I did
If they gave you a set, the struggle must have been real...
You must have faced off with stinkbugs everyday, huh?
It was everyday, yeah.
Everyone was fine with bugs
Everyone was used to the tools, so they were like, "Alright, let's take care of this" ?
Yeah, everyone was like "Okay"
Amazing ww
It was really something
That's crazy. Well, the talk about the mountain is pretty wild, but...
Apparently, well, we just heard about how
you went to a fancy girls' school, but...
Your family is pretty amazing, right?
Your parents are both physicians,
your older brother is a tax accountant, while your cousins
include lawyers, physicians, and certified accountants
With such a predator-class family, do you have any surprising predator-class stories to share?
Isn't your family pretty amazing? What's going on?
My family is... amazing.
Everyone's pretty smart, huh?
Everyone's smart. Besides me, everyone is really, really amazing.
Even if you say that, Nose-san wasn't so bad at academics, right?
Academics.. well, if I tried, I could do them.
So you were intelligent from the beginning, huh?
TLN: Not sure. I heard, 協調性, but doesn't seem right, so made an educated guess.
I was probably quite smart
True, I guess if you watch how book-smart streamers are,
you'll probably just say, "Well, they're streamers, after all!"
Yeah, I think that it's often
swept under the rug "because I'm a streamer"
It's almost as if it's better for streamers to be less book-smart, right?
It's practically a personality trait at this point.
That's really true
This is a bit of a difficult topic, but
"Uruha-jou's family is well-known to be predator-class,
but did Uruha-jou ever have a time when she wanted
to become a lawyer or doctor herself?"
Did you?
I did. I wanted to become a doctor
Really? Amazing!
You wanted to pursue medical school?
Yeah, I thought that I wanted to study medicine
But you were exiled into the mountains and weren't able to return to school, right.. ?
Yeah.. In elementary school, I wrote that I wanted to become a doctor to help my grandfather
Your grandfather would cry tears of happiness if he heard that
Well, he's no longer around, though ww
But, looking back, I was so much more impressive back then than I am now... it kind of scares me.
My elementary school self...
So you gradually lost your drive as the years went by..
I'm sort of like, "How did I end up like this?"
But, results-wise, you've really blossomed as a streamer, so it's fine, but..
Ultimately, it's all good, but I never planned for this
I see.. So, many things happened for you to end up here
That's... I don't think that, in elementary school,
I'd have ever thought that I'd be talking with Inuyama Tamaki like we are now
That's certainly true ww
With that, I'd like to hear about why you chose to join VSpo.
"When you joined VSpo, you mentioned that you went along with your mother to meet the manager.
What kind of things did you talk about? I'd like to hear more about what happened then."
As for how you became a VTuber, weren't you scouted?
I think you've mentioned this before.
Ah, that's right. I was invited.. the managers were like, "How about it?"
But I was a degenerate NEET at the time, so..
Degenerate NEET www
Like, rather than continuing such a worthless lifestyle,
I thought, maybe I could stream a bit, and if I can earn money,
it would at least help my parents out
Your motivation.. !!
That's how it was at the start
Well, well, certainly, umm.. rather than spending all day playing games,
streaming might be better, but... ! Would it? It would.. ?
Like, right now, I've got fans, but I wasn't thinking about that at all back then.
I thought, "Whatever, nobody's going to watch me, anyway."
I was like, "If they're going to pay me, then it's better than what I have going for me right now."
I see, so you started off quite casually, right?
Very much so
So it seems like you went to the manager(s) with your
mother, but was your mother worried at all about this?
Ah, she was. She came along because she was worried
Ahh.. like, "What are VTubers? What's VSpo?"
Right, right.. She was like, "What's streaming?", and,
I was only just given an invitation, so she was like, "Is this legit?"
She was like, "You're sure you're not being tricked?"
Right, that's how parents would think, right?
Yeah, so the manager, my mother, and I... the three of us ended up meeting.
Well, my mother had more questions for them than I did.
Oh, like "How is this going to work?"
"What do you mean by streaming?"
"Ultimately, what's going to happen?"
To ask about the outcome, that's certainly expected for a parent.
Yeah, she did ask about that
Well, that's certainly important, right?
While they were talking, I was just like, "Huh...." while
drinking juice that was bought with my mother's money
Ah, but, now, your mother is quite into VTubers -- does she like Reid-kun?
Ah, she likes Reid-san, and she's really cute.
Like, she's really just an ordinary old woman,
so she doesn't understand the Internet at all.
I see, I see
There was a collaboration in which Reid's goods were being sold online,
but she couldn't figure it out, so she went directly to the store
She searched around, then asked, "Do you have Reid-san's goods in store?"
Then, she contacted me, "They didn't have them." I thought that that was really cute.
She really wanted them.
Buy them for her.
Recently, she's been sleeping on my friend's cushion
Is that so? ww
Yup
Your mother's cute
She is, isn't she? She's totally fallen down the rabbit hole
This sort of stuff (VTubers) is surprisingly fun, the more you watch it.
It gets you hooked, right?
With that, let's move on...
"Uruha-san failed the last examination for her driver's license,
wrote the exam for Eiken Level 2, but failed because of the interview,
It seems like Uruha-san always lets qualifications escape her at the last moment.
I'd like to hear about Uruha-san's certifications, or
if she has any that she'd like to pursue in the future."
There you have it.
First off, there's something I'm curious about.
Can we start with your driver's license?
Well, it's as they wrote, right?
Is that something people fail?
Not that I know of, no.
Right? I've never heard of such a thing, either
TLN: Apologies if unclear. I'm also not familiar with the JP licensing system.
There aren't many people who fail, but I graduated from the driving school
I finished the last exam from the driving school, and,
after that, I had up to one year to get my license
I took the license exam, failed, and thought that it was annoying, so..
I didn't go (again)
Then, I forgot about it, going about my daily life.
When I finally remembered about it, it was just around the one-year mark.
It was like, "Tomorrow would be one year"
That's impressive of you
But I thought that studying would be too troublesome,
so I thought that I'd probably get by if I just studied on the train,
So I got on the train and opened the textbook for the first time in a year, flipped through it, failed, and then..
I was like, "Crap, I failed. What should I do?"
That's not where you go, "What should I do?"
That when I started to panic
You panicked after you failed? ww
I failed, and then I panicked
I think you probably had a bunch of other chances to panic that year, though?
No, but, I honestly forgot about it completely.
To the point that I wondered how I so thoroughly forgot about it.
On the other hand, your mental was strong
Normally, there's no way you'd forget
Really... I didn't even panic in the testing center
In fact, my stomach was hurting, so, rather than failing,
I was more concerned about whether I'd have an accident.
I was really conscious about that.
Like, if you had an accident, your life would be over
Yeah, failing would be better, in comparison
That might be true
Compared to having an accident at the center
Failing would be much better than becoming a legend
That's all I was thinking about, initially.
When I failed, I really started panicking
So do you still not have a driver's license now?
I don't, not at all.
I want VSpo to do some sort of official project where you get your driver's license
Yeah, well, I do think that it might be better to get it
Well, it's convenient for identification
TLN: Quick Google search tells me My Number is some sort of identification service
That's right, but, recently, you have My Number, right?
I guess that's true
So if you got My Number, you wouldn't need a driver's license
Certainly, if you lived in the city, you wouldn't need it
Well, the driver's license is fine and all, but
you "wrote the exam for Eiken Level 2, but failed because of the interview"...
Why did you fail?
Well, like, interviews are, like... lame, right?
TLN: Not sure, maybe this is some sort of required courtesy.
I mean, you get nervous, and.. knocking on the door multiple times.
I mean, however many times you knock doesn't make a difference, right?
I guess that's true, being "Pardon my intrusion" and all is...
I don't like the rigid formalities and such...
I hate everything (about interviews)
Writing Eiken Level 2 is honestly very impressive,
so you might as well do the interview if you've gotten that far..
That's right, isn't it?
Such a waste..
But I had to prioritize my aversion to interviews, no matter what
I don't like stress, you see
Ah, it's tiring, right?
I don't want to be stressed, and... if I'm stressed, I'll fail everything, for real
That's why, I'm really weak to my aversion to stress, so.. I didn't go (to the interview)
Ah, then, even if you did go to the interviews,
if you were stressed, you wouldn't have been able to think properly?
Either way, you'd have failed?
That's right. That's what I thought, so I quit, but..
Ultimately, when I asked my teacher at school,
apparently 70-80% of people who pass the written examination also pass the interview
That's how it seems, or so I've heard from my friends
Like, the interview's fine, as long as you show up
So I thought that I maybe should have gone
Such a waste, really
It really is
Such a waste... Nose-san, do you have other qualifications?
I probably do, but I don't remember.
TLN: Eiken and KanKen are English and Kanji proficiency tests, respectively. Eiken Level 2 is classified as "high school graduate"-level, but not many high school or college students complete this certification.
Eiken, Kanken, and such..
Also, things that our school made us do
I see, you do seem like you do (have more)
Yeah, but, I didn't take any, so I don't have any certifications.
I have no proof, so I basically have nothing.
That's what I thought, after talking with you for the past hour!
I knew you had more, but you just wouldn't be able to remember.
Yesterday, I didn't look at it closely, but I found some sort of certificate in my room, from some sort of exam.
Ah, finally something proper!
Right, however, there was a coffee stain covering about half of it
No way! Really, Nose-san's room is like a jungle
Yeah, but, I probably thought that it was bad, so
I probably just kept ignoring it and left it alone, however many years ago
So that's how half of it turned brown, right?
I see... Then, let's move on to this..
"Nose-san went to a vocational school, and, for a bread-making exam,
she forgot to bring crucial ingredients, such as cake/pastry flour. Is that true?"
Does bread made with cake flour not rise?
It doesn't rise. You're well-informed, aren't you?
I don't really know much about cooking, as I'm bad at it, but I thought that'd be the case..
It doesn't rise...
But, it's surprising, like, all of these questions, there's nothing I would ask (or asked)
True, there were some pointing out your cute parts, but not in any of the questions.
Right, like, I've been responding to everything, but they've all been, you know...
Conversely, we had someone say,
TLN: Uh... how about no? Translating 1 hour is already kicking my butt, sorry.
"This girl has so many crazy stories to tell that one hour won't be enough. Please make it two or three hours."
Ahh, I see
You probably have too many stories to tell
Like, umm.. Bread is..
TLN: You can probably tell, but the sentence is very fragmented. If I translated directly, it wouldn't make any sense.
The bread-making/cooking exam was compulsory at the school I went to
That's impressive! The school's quite put-together
I had to take the cooking exam, otherwise I'd have to repeat a school year, but I thought it was lame, so..
Half of your life is lame, huh?
That's true, right? I mean, I really dislike being stressed out, so..
You're bringing THAT up again?!
It's like, you know, if we're talking about other exams, there was also an exam on apple-peeling.
Wow, you did that sort of thing?
Yeah, everyone had to peel apples in silence, and we were being timed..
Oh, they were timing you?
TLN: Not sure how this works.
They'd start timing after you had finished half of it., and...
I couldn't stand that environment, so...
Being timed adds pressure, after all
That's right.
That's why, I was able to get over the apple exam, and
there was also a Swiss roll exam.
I managed to get through that, too
It finally came time for the bread exam, and I felt, "This is lame."
TLN: Tamaki is pointing out that Ichinose sounded as if she had been waiting for it.
It "finally" came, huh?
That's what I was thinking, and, well..
That's right.. At the time, well, you use bread flour to make bread, but..
TLN: 強力粉, lit. strong flour. High gluten. vs, 薄力粉, lit. thin/weak flour. Cake flour.
Sure
But I mistakenly brought cake flour with me instead
Oh, I see
Pure white bread.... What was it, again, I don't remember.
It doesn't sound like it'd taste good
Right, but appearance-wise, it looked like bread, so I thought that I wouldn't be found out.
I see, I see. You thought you'd be able to fool them.
I missed the exam, but, on on that day,
the instructor had prepared all the ingredients for us.
There were no mistakes with the ingredients, but
I took the exam myself later on, so they told me to bring all the ingredients from home
I had to bring bread flour, but I mistakenly brought cake flour instead
Huh..? No, in the first place, you shouldn't have missed the exam!
True
So this would have never happened if you didn't miss the exam?
That's right. I was alone, doing the exam,
and realized, "Wait, don't I need bread flour?"
"What I brought, isn't this cake flour?!"
But I gave it a try anyway
You wouldn't know if you didn't try, after all
I was able to make something that looked like bread
I didn't think they'd notice, but, of course, they did
On the contrary, to think that professionals wouldn't notice, aren't you the amazing one?
What kind of mental do you have?
Professionals are amazing, aren't they?
What are you saying? You're something else, yup...
They'd, like, know just from looking, but could find out instantly if they tasted it
In the first place, don't fail the exam
At the time, I honestly thought that I'd be in a pinch if I failed
Don't "honestly" me
To fail.. !! In the first place, being given a chance to redo the exam is quite amazing
They were really nice
I see. We're getting to know better and better what kind of person you are.
Here we go, this is what I've been dying to ask you the entire day.
"Out of all the stories from Nose-san, the one that I find most memorable is how she feels that she has to pretend
to be in a phone call when going to the convenience store.
I'd like to know if she still pretends to be on the phone to visit the convenience store."
Why do you pretend to be on the phone?
So we're finishing with this, huh? Well, you see...
For meals, well...  I really dislike leaving the house, so..
I imagine..
If I leave the house once, I won't want to go out again for the rest of the day.
I can see that
So when I go out to buy food,
I only want to leave the house once,
so I buy all three meals at once, you see?
Oh... you buy everything
Yeah, I do
And you eat it all, right?
So then -- Yeah, www
I can't really finish everything, though
So, when I'm going there to buy my three meals,
I worry that the staff might think,
"Is she really going to eat all this by herself?"
Well, they probably don't care at all about that
True, and they might not even
look at what you're buying
Right, but I'm extremely needlessly conscious of others, so..
And because I didn't like that,
After thinking about how to avoid it,
what I came up with was..
Before entering the convenience store,
I hold my phone with one hand up to my ear
and pretend that I'm being asked
by a friend, no, my parents,
to buy their share of food as well
I act out that sort of situation
So you roleplay? lol
Ah, yes. Roleplay.
I used to always do that when
entering convenience stores
Nobody would pay attention to that, you know?
Nobody cares, right? I get that.
Cute
But I couldn't stop doing it
Are you still doing that now?
No, I've stopped
Oh! Nose-san's grown up!
You don't feel embarrassed anymore?
Right, after talking lots with my listeners about these things
like how I can't help but feel self-conscious..
Like, even now, I can't go out to eat by myself, but..
After having many of these conversations,
everyone was like, "You're fine, don't worry about it."
There were also listeners who listened seriously
And thanks to that,
Thanks to that, I've gotten better
Oh, isn't that great, Nose-san?
That's right
Thank you, all my listeners
Is it because you can't eat alone that you can't go out to restaurants alone?
I can't eat out by myself.
This is sort of going back to what I said earlier about
being in a driving school, but I'd buy my lunch, and,
we still had classes in the afternoon, right?
Ah, yes, yes
At those times, I took my lunch with me to eat in the washroom alone
You'd go that far?!
Yeah, I don't want people to see me eating
Because it's embarrassing to you?
Well, when you're eating, you lose awareness of your surroundings
You're vulnerable, right?
That's right. I don't want strangers to see me like that
I was really self-conscious about that
That's crazy www
That's right. There are probably people
who are like, "Do 'toilet meals' really exist?"
I think I can even put this on my resume
Since it's so rare
That's amazing.
So, it's not because you're lonely that you can't eat out alone,
Rather, you feel embarrassed if you're seen eating
Like, I don't want others to see me eating...
I see..
I don't eat out alone simply because it's lonely,
which I thought was probably a trait of being a
middle-aged man living with his parents, but
our ways of thinking were completely different, huh?
That's part of it, too, but the biggest factor is definitely
not wanting to be seen by strangers
Nose-san is definitely very conscious of how others see her
That's probably the case
I see, think that that's pretty cute
Thank you
I'll have my meals in the toilet, but thank you
You eat in the toilet, but there's something cute about that!
Just barely!
Just barely
Alright, then, moving on...
"Were there any reasons that made you change from
TLN: 'Jackknife' was Ichinose's moniker early on, due to her "blunt" and "frank" nature, as well as her "tumultuous life before joining VSpo."
your original "Jackknife" personality, to the cute Ichinose Uruha we know today?"
Well, I think the "Jackknife" period was pretty much your debut, but..
You were fairly harsh with your words, back then, weren't you?
I was.
To give a reason, it's simply that all kinds of people
started watching me, so I got scared of being cancelled.
That's why?!
So it's not because you gained a lot of viewers and you wanted to satisfy them, that you became kinder?
Ah! Initially, I didn't really..
I always thought of myself as a pretty good person, so
That's how I thought from the start, so, even though
I'm foul-mouthed and am harsh with my words,
I didn't think I was an unpleasant person
So it became a question of whether that would be perceived or not,
and well, I didn't want to get cancelled, so yeah.
By the way, I actually have a related question here,
"Nose-san had an incident where she asked Nijisanji's Kanae-san, off-stream, "What kind of person are you?",
which she revealed two years after the incident had happened.
If Nose-san could say one thing to herself back in those early days, what would she say?"
So, to Kanae-san.. www
No, well, this...
This was, well, literally right after I had just debuted.
I didn't know anything about VTubers or streamers.
I didn't know who was out there
I see. Nose-san wasn't familiar with VTubers beforehand, right?
That's right, the only VTuber I knew was probably Kizuna Ai.
With that, well, I didn't know anything, and,
while I was gaming with a friend,
They asked me, "Do you know Nijisanji's Kanae-san?",
and I said, "Well, I've heard of the name, at least."
We had that exchange, and, afterwards, we were
talking about getting some more people to join
our game, so they asked, "Want to ask Kanae-san?"
And, at the time, I had never interacted with any VTubers outside VSpo
So, it was a first time meeting anyone from the outside
TLN: Apparently another accepted TL would be 'bastard'...
So, I wondered, "What are the blokes outside like?"
Wait up, wait up! Calling him a "bloke" is already not good!
So, I was wondering about what them blokes would be like
You're crazy!
So, I was like, "Ok, let's give it a try."
"What's this Kanae feller like?"
Stop that, seriously!
It was like that, but, honestly, I said it like a joke, initially
But, then, my friend actually told Kanae-san
Stop it! Don't tell him, seriously!
Yeah, I initially meant it as a joke, but my friend actually went and asked him
Stop it, the off-stream vibe is --
So, he was like, "Huh?"
Kanae-san would be surprised, so stop it!
That's what happened, so I think I left a horrible first impression.
Well, he actually told me so.
But, Kanae-san's a kind person, so he wouldn't get mad over something like that.
That's right, it's good that he's a nice person
Good thing it was Kanae-san, right? Since he's a fairly kind person
Even now, I still think so
If it were someone else, they might have gotten mad
Things could have gone south
Seriously, be thankful to Kanae-san...
I am, honestly
I'm glad (it was Kanae-san)
That's too funny. Then, here's the final question..
"Speaking of Uruha-jou, she's among the VSpo
members who have common sense, but who does she think in VSpo is the most off-the-rails?"
Let's wrap up by talking about VSpo...
How about it? In your opinion, does VSpo have a 'craziest' member?
Who's the craziest in VSpo?
Seriously off-the-rails... If we're talking about someone
who's got a few screws loose, then it's Sumire, surely.
I see, everyone says Su-chan, huh? So, it's her, after all?
Sumire's a bit.. bizarre.
Ah, she's strange, is she?
I thought that she was strange ,but cute
She's strange, yeah.
The more I  interact with her, the more I think something's off about her
I guess, if we're talking about someone who can't interact normally with others, it'd be Su-chan, huh?
That's right. You can't interact normally --
Sometimes, I wonder how she's managed to survive so long
Wait, but, that goes for you, too, you know?
That's probably true ww
Everyone probably thinks so, but I'm the same when I see Sumire
I see, so we've had another vote for Su-chan
Alright, thank you very much
Have any other members been here?
Others.. There was Nazu-chan, and, who else? Lisa-chan, I guess?
Ah, I guess, they're all about the same
Ah, so they're all the same, huh?
Yup, they are